Jeffrey Jeronis

Lead Electrical Engineer

Levittown, PA - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Jeffrey-Jeronis/6c68df5f53c10de2

15 Years experience from component to system level design. DOD related work and testing/verification. Fluent with all test equipment, oscilloscopes, spectrum anaylizers, Digital Volt Meters, power supplies. Prepare and present technical presentations for customers. Fluent with Word, Excel, PowerPoint. Interested in R&D projects and expanding the scope of current projects.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Lead Electrical Engineer

Navmar Applied Sciences Corporation (NASC) - June 2004 to September 2011

Lead Electrical Engineer for TigerShark UAV Program: Responsibilities included wiring design, integration of all avionics, field testing, introduction to manufacturing and field support of deployed aircraft. Extensive travel required for qualification and acceptance testing of aircraft.

Systems Engineer: Responsible for O&S (Operations and Support) and logistical support of DOD deployed imagery systems. Fielded calls from various worldwide locations to expedite solutions/repairs for any problems encountered in the field. Also responsible for maintaining yearly maintenance contracts and configuration management of the various deployed systems.

Lead Electrical Engineer

Piasecki Aircraft Corporation - June 2002 to June 2004

Responsible for all aspects of electrical design pertaining to the modification of a Blackhawk helicopter. The modification replaces the conventional tail rotor with a Piasecki VTDP (Vectored Thrust Ducted Prop) configuration. See www.piasecki.com for further details. Responsibilities included the design, purchasing, manufacturing liaison and direction of two electromechanical technicians pertaining to the modification. Also responsible for generating specifications of special item parts, test procedures for new systems and engineering support for testing of other systems, i.e. mechanical, hydraulic. Electrical systems consist of control surface actuation, cockpit display indication and aircraft instrumentation. Instrumentation includes strain gages, potentiometers, accelerometers, pressure transducers, temperature transducers, and chip detectors.

Electrical Engineer

Smiths Industries Aerospace - October 2000 to December 2002

Responsible for the design, development, introduction to manufacturing and manufacturing support of solid state cockpit displays. Also responsible for qualification testing of said displays. Qualification consisted of EMI/RFI conformance (DO160), vibration, temperature and environmental testing. Generated ECRs/ECNs modifying designs to meet specifications and generated qualification test reports upon successful completion of tests.

Electrical Engineer

Litton Special Devices - March 1994 to October 2000

Responsible for the electrical design of closed-loop servo systems. Projects included brush, 3-phase brushless and stepper motor designs, all used for military applications. Worked with mechanical engineers to define customer specifications and develop solutions to conform with the specifications. Designed test equipment, generated ATPs, performed MTBF calculations (MIL-STD-217), qualification testing, reports and supported

introduction to manufacturing for all designs. Other projects included a power supply redesign for a cockpit indicator line, reducing power consumption by 30%.

EDUCATION

Electronics and Controls

BSEE Drexel University 1996

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Skills

Signal Integrity Training
Soldering Certification, MIL-STD-2000
Computer Literate, Word, Excel ect.
Engineering Software: Autocad, Mentor Graphics, Electronics Workbench